

Contact
Phone: +66 974654954
Email: supachai.tansuwan@gmail.com

My Portfolio shorturl.at/choyV (Data Analytics, Data Science, Data Visualization Portfolio)

Computer Skills

- SQL
- Python
- Business Intelligence BI tools (Tableau, Power BI, Google Data Studio)
- Dataiku
- Microsoft Azure
- ACL (CAATs: Computer Assisted Audit Techniques)
- ERP (SAP)
- MS Office

Professional Trainings with Certificates

- Microsoft Certified Azure Data Fundamentals (2021)
- Microsoft Certified Azure AI Fundamentals (2021)
- SQL for Data Analytics (2021)
- Hands-on Data Science and Machine Learning (2021)
- Data Science Essential Class 3 (2021)
- The Business Intelligence Analyst (2020)
- Innovation with Data Analytics and Visualization (2020)

Skills and Strengths

- Good sense of both business and IT/data with effective communication between business and technical users
- Knowledge in data analytics, data science and data engineer
- Good at English communication skills
- Fair in Japanese communication skills
- Fast learner, Good Team Player, Friendly, Optimistic, Open-Minded, Collaboration
- Passion for learning new digital and data skills

Supachai Tansuwan

(Master degree in Management of Analytics and Data Technologies with Business and Accounting Background)

Background and Objective

A Business Intelligence with six years of experience in many industries with knowledge in business process/flow, finance& accounting, information/data technology, data analytics and machine learning/AI. I seek opportunities to learn and improve my digital and data skills to pursue a career in any data field. Therefore, I am interested in data/BI analyst, project manager (data/digital transformation project), business analyst, data translator or any appropriate position where I can effectively utilize and contribute my skills and knowledge, especially digital and data skills, to help company achieve its goals and missions.

Working Experience

• GSK Thailand: Business Intelligence (July 2022 - Present)

- Maintain all master data/ reference files that related to sales dashboards/ reports
- Validate market research reports from third-party and make the report to be available for business users.
- Prepare local standard analysis reports to commercial teams.
- Collaborate with regional team for updating needed information, managing users and any other incidents of existing sales dashboards/ reports.
- o Develop new dashboards to support commercial teams.
- Provide data/information as requested
- Automate data preparation and other administrative tasks
- Train sales representative to use Power BI Dashboard

ShopeePay: Financial Planning& Analyst (December 2021 - June 2022)

- Analyze and present financial performance weekly to management and find insights that drive change of performance.
- Develop data flow model for automated updated daily related financial data for tracking& monitoring performance.
- o Support data for budgeting& forecast, including short term and long term forecast
- Query ad-hoc data as requested

• EXIM Bank Thailand: Data Analytics Auditor (September 2020 - November 2021)

- Lead and manage teams for implementing offsite audit/ continuous audit (datadriven) to detect fraud/error in timely manners, analyze root cause for improving business process and reduce internal auditor's workload
- o Plan and set timeline for implementing offsite audit/ continuous audit
- Understand business process/task & data to analyze risks for searching new rule based
- Communicate and coordinate with business users in other departments, internal auditors and my teams to develop rule based/condition by coding script to extract unusual data and inspect the findings with internal auditors
- Support data to internal auditor as requested
- Use Business Intelligence tools to prepare interactive dashboards to support internal audit, present management, and ad-hoc requests. (Please see more detail in My Portfolio)

Mitsubishi Motor: Risk Management& Compliance (April 2020 - August 2020)

- Prepare personal data policies and related materials to comply with Thailand's Personal Data Protection Act (PDPA)
- Coordinate and cooperate with other departments to prepare records of processing activities (ROPA) related to PDPA

PricewaterhouseCoopers ABAS: Risk Assurance - IT (October 2018 - March 2020)

- Understand business and IT internal control of clients
- Test IT application control and IT general control (access to program and data, change management, computer operations)
- o Report findings and recommend improvements
- o Involve in Thailand's Personal Data Protection Act (PDPA) audit project
- Analyze, clean, code script and extract unusual data to financial auditor by using CAATs tool (ACL)

• SCG: Internal Auditor (March 2018 - September 2018)

- o Provide the value added to internal process/task for organization
- Recommend organizations for preventing, detecting and investigating fraud
- Report internal audit findings and recommend improvements

PricewaterhouseCoopers ABAS: Core Assurance – Financial Auditor (July 2016 -February 2018)

- Understand and prepare client's business process/flow such as purchasing and sales process
- Define and test key control that impact financial statements
- o Analyze comparative profit & loss and detail of balance sheet
- o Audit financial statements, misstatements and fraud
- Report financial audit findings and recommend improvements

Education

 Master: National Institute of Development Administration (NIDA), Graduate School of Applied Statistics (2021 – Expected 2023)

Major in Management of Analytics and Data Technologies (MADT)

 Bachelor: Chulalongkorn University, Faculty of Commerce and Accountancy (2011 – 2015)

Major in Accounting, GPA: 3.19/4.00

Other Awards& Recognitions

- TOEIC 870
- Japanese-Language Proficiency (Level 4 = N5)
- Grade 5 Piano (Trinity Guildhall)
- Ethics and Morality (2006 2011)

Participation in university& school activities

- "Dkunna" Clip Contest, Chulalongkorn University (2014)
- Staff, Movie and Mind Training, Chulalongkorn University (2013)
- Staff Nisitsampan, Banshi Seminar2012, Chulalongkorn University (2012)
- Staff, CU TU traditional basketball, Thammasat University (2012)
- Staff, 30th Anniversary MBA Always Reconnect, Chulalongkorn University, CU Open house, Chulalongkorn University (2012)
- Volunteer for packing feedstuff, Chulalongkorn University (2012)
- Staff, C.U. Academic Expo2012, Chulalongkorn University (2012)
- Competitor, Bandshi Acoustic Contest, Chulalongkorn University (2012)
- Competitor, Basketo and Basketee Audition2011, Chulalongkorn University (2011)
- Attended Grid Technology Training, Kasetsart University (2010)
- Participated in English camps once a year (2005 2009)